<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pedro Carmona</title>
    <link>https://pedrocarmona.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pedro Carmona</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 23:50:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pedrocarmona.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Website Development</title>
      <link>https://pedrocarmona.github.io/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 23:50:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrocarmona.github.io/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is the first day of this personal website, which I chosen to develep with &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while a go, I had the opportunity to work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, developing a yet to come, new version for my parents small scale
tourist resort, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quintadaricafe.pt/&#34;&gt;Quinta da Rica-Fe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After working with both &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, I decided that I will migrate also to Hugo my parents website. The main reasons for this are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile time, Hugo is really fast comparing with the alternative. Also, in jekyll file changes detetion is slow. In hugo, imidiatly after saving the files the changes are propagated to the browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although it is just a tool on top of golang, it will allow me to get used to golang templating and stack trace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the time of this article, github only serves Github Pages with Jekyll. This means that &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;some work arounds&lt;/a&gt; are necessary to use Hugo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To fully compare both platforms, I need a project like my parents website - where there are requirements like two languages, Portuguese and English.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pedrocarmona.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 19:00:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pedrocarmona.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pedro is a Software Engineer at Bidmath in Amsterdam. In his job, he chases the increase of impressions, clicks and conversions in Bidmath advertisment platform. Rethinks and implements, but mostly has fun, developing Ruby applications and services, along with Docker and Kubernetes. At the same time, activily running away from Hadoop, to play with data in Jupyter and Apache Beam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015 worked at Fidelity National Information Services as a Programmer Analyst I for one year. From the Amsterdam&amp;rsquo;s office developed and mantained banking software, such as webservices integration and frontend interfaces for telephony  and for user management using Java, Spring and Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Received MsC in Computer Engineering in 2014 from the University of Coimbra, Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During his studies, also worked as Web Developer for Whitesmith, consulting in a venue reservation system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>